Abid Akram UI/UX Designer

≥ abid.akram01@gmail.com

Pengaluru, India

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/abidakram

+919026553313

Passport - P7793753

https://www.abidakram.notion.site

UX designer and developer with 5+ years of experience and specialization in designing enterprise tools and software. I enjoy turning complex problems into simple, beautiful, and intuitive interface designs focusing on crafting a user-friendly experience and using data to discover insights, understand users better, and predict actions.

Skills & Tools

Design (Product Design, User Experience Design, Interaction Design, Mobile Design, Web Design, Prototyping)

Research (User Research, Usability Testing, Personas & Scenarios)

Collaboration (Project Management, Communication, Problem Solving)

Frontend Technologies (HTML5, CSS3, Angular, SCSS, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Material Design)

Tools (Figma, Adobe XD, Notion, Zeplin, InVision)

Experience

UI/UX Designer

Cisco System India Pvt Ltd

2022/04 – present | Bengaluru, India

- Led end-to-end Phoenix platform UX redesign, creating an intuitive interface that streamlined data and modeling pipeline development for developers and business stakeholders alike.
- Translated design visions into high-performance HTML/CSS code, ensuring consistent and pixel-perfect visual experiences across multiple platforms, while using Figma to effectively communicate design intent.
- Collaborate with the manager and business stakeholders for new features to Phoenix, getting users more interested and making their work easier. Teamed up with different groups to collect ideas, tested changes with users, and consistently improved the platform.

Software Engineer UI

Open Financial Technologies Pvt Ltd

2019/01 - 2022/04 | Bengaluru, India

- Designed and developed the OpenMoney Web App, a dynamic platform that enables users to seamlessly connect their bank accounts to pay vendors, receive payments, and reconcile transactions effortlessly.
- Collaborated closely with UX designers to translate user requirements into functional and visually captivating user interfaces.
- Build UX design and developed the OpenHub Web App for online B2B marketplace, connecting buyers with suppliers.

UI Developer

Quess Corp Ltd (IBM India Pvt Ltd)

2018/04 – 2019/01 | Bengaluru, India

- Led the UI development for the IBM Marketplace, an e-commerce platform facilitating the purchase and sale of new or refurbished laptops exclusively for IBM internal employees.
- Conducted A/B testing to optimize design elements, leading to a 60% increase in successful transactions.
- Utilized Agile methodologies to lead sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and retrospectives, fostering a collaborative and iterative development environment.

Education

Master in Computer Application

Uttar Pradesh Technical University 2013 - 2016

Master in Commerce

Kanpur University

2012 - 2013

Bachelor in Commerce

Lucknow University

2008 - 2011

Certificates

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design \square Google

Angular (Intermediate) Certificate 2

HackerRank

Awards

MAKING A DIFFERENCE

Cisco

2023

Awarded for independently managing the projects, doing it efficiently, and meeting the agreed-upon timeframe.

GETTING TO THE FINISH LINE

Cisco

2022

Awarded for an in-depth and incredibly intuitive design that was highly regarded by the leadership and cross-functional team.

INNOVATE EVERYWHERE

Cisco

2022

Awarded for outstanding achievement and in charge of the 2022 deliveries and stakeholders interactions.

Projects

Phoenix - Advance Analytics Tools - for case study please click here

2022/04 - present

Role: UX Designer and Developer

Phoenix \square is an in-house tool for the Advanced Analytics team. It was created by developers for developers, helping you follow a consistent method to build high-quality pipelines for data and modeling. Phoenix aims to serve as a convenient solution for both developers and business stakeholders.

Open Money Web Apps - for case study please click here

2019 - 2020

Role: Angular UI Developer

Open Money Web Apps is a neo-banking platform that allows the business to create GST Invoices, Send & Receive Payments, Manage Cash Flows, Payment Gateway, Expense Management, Insurance, Automate Payments, etc.

OpenHub Web App 2020 - 2021

Role: Angular UI Developer

OpenHub is an online B2B marketplace, connecting buyers with suppliers. This tool focuses on providing a platform to Small & Medium Enterprises (SMEs), Large Enterprises as well as individuals.

OpenMoney Website - for case study please click here

2021 - 2022

Role: UI Developer

I created a cool OpenMoney website using Angular and HTML. I turned design sketches into a live site with animations that work on different web browsers. I used special tools to make everything look nice and work smoothly. This project shows how good I am at making websites and paying attention to small details.

IBM Marketplace 2018 – 2019

Role: UI Developer and Designer

IBM E-commerce platform that allows to sell and purchase of new or refurbished Laptop for IBM internal Employee

Personal Projects

FlixMovies - for more details please click here

2021 - 2021

Role: Sole Angular UI Developer and Designer

FlixMovies ☑ - It is a free website that allows users to watch movies and TV shows online. The website has a wide variety of movies and TV shows, including both popular and obscure titles.